What do you think about the three guys
you got today?
Uh we're fired up. It's a long wait. You
know, that was that was the toughest
part waiting so long to to pick again,
but
you know, Bobby and JC are two guys that
we had in on in on visits and we're able
to spend
considerable amount of time with those
guys. You know, I know we talked about
the D-tackle position a little bit last
night and we're happy to get him in
here. You know, big body, long, strong,
powerful.
Um you know, JC a guy that played you
know, left tackle there at Illinois. Um
you know, some position flex for him,
you know, tackle, guard. Um you know, we
see some versatility with him. And then
Jack Kelly, you know, another guy we
spent down time with down at the
All-Star game.
Um ran really well, super productive
player. You know, he's playing off the
ball for for BYU at Weber State. You
know, he played off the edge. He's got
30-plus career
sacks. So, a lot of versatility in in
him and you know, also the ability to
play special teams. So,
um clear vision for all three of them,
you know, to compete for roster spots
and um you know, excited to get all
three of these guys.
That was your final scheduled pick of
the draft. What do you make of your year
class as a whole?
You want to do that one? Yeah,
I think I think we got a bunch of
giants, you know, a bunch of
figuratively and literally. We we've got
guys that we really like that are going
to make a difference and to to to Joe's
point, clear vision probably is a really
good way to say it cuz we have a a clear
understanding of how each of these guys
fits in. You even look at Jack at the
end and and compare him to Ar'vell in a
sense. You know, the two bookends on the
on the class, two linebackers and Jack
will be more in the Mike mold, but he'll
also he's also a guy that can rush the
passer off the edge. You know, if you
saw him at Weber State before he
transferred. So, we can move guys around
and put them in different spots. He'll
play special teams. So, got a clear
vision for him as well. Also create
competition in that linebacker room,
which is strong. Um offensive line,
defensive line, defensive tackle. You
know, I I don't be talking about that.
That's still something we got to
continue to address.
Um we're not finished with that at all,
but to be able to add in the draft a guy
we really liked. We're a little
surprised he was probably still there.
He's a guy that we we had hoped would
still be there. We had a couple guys and
he was still standing, but we we love
the way he plays.
Uh he plays the way we like to play. If
he plays square, he locks out, he sheds
blocks. He's a very fundamentally sound
guy. So, uh
so he'll he'll be a part of it and then
we get a couple vets going forward.
You mentioned giant bunch of giants
figured in
in literally. Um
when you took even just including free
agency, there's a clear difference like
the roster, the look of the roster,
right? You're you've added size. You
wanted seems like you want to be bigger
more physical. How much is that
something that was your priority and you
noticed when you came here?
Yeah, definitely a priority. You know,
it's it's it's important, you know, and
there's nothing to you can be a giant in
different kind of ways. You know, you
can be real fast and that makes you that
makes you
a fast giant, I guess, but
just really want really good players. We
want guys that that fit how we want to
play and
and some of these guys, they really fit
how we want to play. The fact that
they're bigger players, longer, you
know, heavy-handed type guys is
important, you know, because especially
in this division, you know, you've got
to play that way. Your interior
offensive line has to be physical. Look
at the defensive tackles in this league,
you know, right down the road
especially.
Um and offensive line the same way, you
know, we want to want to be able to
handle the offensive lines that we've
got to play against up front and of
course we talked about stopping the run
right out of the gates, right? You you
got to be big and strong to do that.
You've got to be athletic, you got to be
able to move. All those things are part
of it, too, but it's a big part of it.
Davis will start out where?
Swing guard and tackle. Swing guard and
tackle. He can play both. That was that
was we just had this conversation and
that that went a long way kind of in
determining where he would play, but
very talented, athletic, long-armed guy.
Can bend, can move his feet. He's big.
Uh he's got he's got some growing to do
as a player, some maturing to do as a
player, but we had him in for a visit,
talked to him about that at length. Very
determined guy and he's he's determined
to
to kind of develop into his talent
level. He's a very talented offensive
lineman.
You guys have both alluded to not being
done at defensive tackle. Where where do
things stand with DJ Reader? He came in
2 weeks ago. Just how did that visit go
and where do you go from there? Yeah,
we've been in contact with you know,
several agents of veteran defensive
tackles. So, you know, we'll we'll
continue to keep those communications
open.
Um you know, we'll see what happens next
week. Maybe have a couple more visits
with some vet guys. So, certainly on our
radar.
How satisfied are you with how you
helped your quarterback Jackson in with
this draft?
I feel really good about it. I I feel
very strongly that we did. You know, it
was definitely a priority to do it,
right? Protect him first of all. You
know, it's hard to complete passes if
you don't have time to throw. And then
give him another weapon, you know, and
try to give him as many weapons as we
can, but to to to get Malachi was
was a big plus. You saw him here for the
pictures and things like that and you
saw he's a good-looking athlete, right?
And good good person.
Another very determined guy. So,
I'd say that was a major priority.
And where where are you with Odell?
Where is that now?
We worked him out. He looked good. We've
just got to kind of continue
conversations with him. I I really like
him. Odell and I are going to talk
Tuesday night. Uh kind of see where he's
at, see where we're at. Um see what he's
thinking, you know, see what we're
thinking now
with the roster and the way it looks and
see if it makes sense. I think if we do
anything, you know, just just being
honest about it. You know, it has to
make sense for the Giants. It has to
make sense for him. And he's in a
different part place in his career for
sure. I think I love about Odell is he's
he's right now he's in such a good place
in terms of
you know, his humility. He wants to be
part of a team. He wants to contribute.
He wants to help the young guys. That's
what he's talking about doing. He still
thinks he has he has some juice, you
know. And he and he looked good in the
workout. So,
um you still got to be able to play, you
know. It's not going to be the old
Odell. You know, it's going to be a
different version, the 2.0 Odell, I
guess you'd say, but
uh we're not decided on that yet. He's
not quite decided on that yet. I think
we have to just kind of see where we're
at this next week.
John, you came in here 4 months ago. You
didn't really know Joe, his staff,
anybody in the building super well, I
can imagine. Just [clears throat] as you
look back, you went through free agency,
the draft, trades, everything. Like how
do you feel like this operation has
gone? Yeah, that's good. Thanks for
asking that. I I I feel great about how
it's gone, you know, and
starting from the maybe from the ground
up, you know, looking at the the staff
and the scouts and everything.
It's a great group. It's a great group
that Joe put together. On the scouting
side, I feel like uh I feel like they're
they're thorough. Uh they're excellent
at what they do. I saw I saw them work.
I saw the reports. I saw them through
the process even the last 3 days.
The communication communication one of
the best things that this this scouting
department does is communicate with the
coaches. The coaches and the scouts are
just seamless. We ended up on the same
page. We didn't always agree, but we
understood where we were coming from and
then we had probably the most important
thing is to have a clear understanding
of when you bring a place. My dad always
used to say in recruiting, it's not who
you don't get, it's who you get that
matters. You know, do you have a clear
vision for what they're going to do? Do
do you like them as a player? And can
you find a place for them and get them
ready to play? So, I think we did that,
you know, and communication's a big part
of that. So, happy with that. Joe and I
have been working together every single
day. I mean, hours on end. Uh whether
it's planning or organizing or or just
talking about players or watching tape
again over and over again on these guys.
And I feel like it's going very well. I
I think if you look at the draft and you
want to talk about results, yeah, we'll
talk about results down the road. We got
to find out. We'll see, you know, it's
like all these draft classes. You don't
know
until they get out there and start
playing, but uh on the surface right
now, I I I feel great about it. I don't
feel we could have done any better. I
think we made the most of the draft,
made the most of the resources we had.
And I'm really really happy with the way
it went. I hope I hope Joe feels the
same.
John, does bringing does bringing an
overall philosophy to team building into
a draft help clarify what direction you
want to go in when certain picks come
up? Like saying we want to be bigger, we
want to be this kind of team. When
you're looking at the grades, does that
help clarify
kind of where you go and what
tiebreakers happen when picks come up?
Uh it's a fair point. Like I I think it
happens through the process. To your
point, like we didn't sit there and say,
you know, no one said, "Hey, put this is
the philosophy, so to speak." That
happens in the conversations, you know,
so as you start talking about players,
you start talking about your roster. You
know, back and forth conversation. It
just you try to paint a picture, you
know, and and it's it's in it's back and
forth, okay?
You know, what do you see? What are we
looking for?
What do you see in this player? How does
he fit? How does he fit? Because all
every player brings something different
to the table and you want to
you want to have the type of guys that
fit how you want to play, but you want
to play the the way the way your guys
play, too. So,
I think it's part of the process. I
don't think it's like you're dictating
anything really. You're just you're just
you you're
you're dialoguing about it. And you come
to an understanding through that
communication. Right? Make sense? Yes.
How do you guys approach now the
the draft after the draft, the idea of
young drafted guys? Where are you
[snorts] at roster-wise? John, I don't
know your philosophy through the years
and Joe,
you know, how you guys do it. How do you
handle
what comes next as far as that goes?
Yeah, we've been working on it for
weeks. So, you know, again, talking
about the communication with the
coaching staff and our scouts.
Um you know, we've been well ahead of
this. You know, a lot of it is um you
know, relationship based for some of
these kids. So, whether we're sending
coaches out, working kids out privately,
going to pro days, meeting with them at
All-Star games. You know, it's all part
of the process from first round to
seventh round and then priority free
agent. So,
um you know, the recruiting process has
been ongoing. They're up there meeting
now. And then as soon as the draft's
over, then you know, we'll attack it. We
have a really good plan in place. You
know, we've got targeted players. Again,
the coaches, the analysts, our scouts,
uh coach and I, you know, Don, the
entire scouting staff has been working
on, you know, a plan for free agency
over the last couple of weeks. So, you
know, we're ready to go. Have you guys
set a fixed number as far as how many
guys you can bring in or is it is it
flexible? Yeah, yeah, that's a yeah,
we've got It's a great question. We've
had that conversation. That's a lot
today, all right. It's It's It's It's
It's a fixed flexible number. Fixed
flexible number is a good way to put it.
>> We got a number, but you know, it
depends on who you can get.
>> Yeah. Because and I would I maybe if
we're talking about philosophy, I just
kind of say this. It's like we're all
trying to make the roster better. So,
there's guys, but then there's always
the ability to to to to turn your roster
and you're always going to be looking to
improve it. So, just it just depends,
you know, you're going to have the best
90 that you can possibly get and you're
going to have the best 53 that you can
possibly get and you're going to have
the best 16 on the practice squad that
you can possibly get. And that's all you
always got to be working at.
John, what was your Two more. What was
your opinion on
Malik Nabers' opinions on your guys'
first round pick?
>> Oh, yeah, it's a good question. Now, we
had a great conversation with that.
Malik came in the next morning, you
know, and sat up there and we were
talking about it. You know, he he made
him he made himself clear. It's like he
even said, I if you you go back and you
watch it, you know, I appreciated kind
of where he was coming from. I mean, you
know, it's uh it's uh you're you're
you're in a podcast and you're talking
ball and he's just like, well, how they
going to use the guy, you know, how's he
going to play, you know, and you know, I
like don't get me wrong. He said, don't
get me wrong and I think maybe we got
him wrong, you know, it's out there a
little bit because that's what's what we
do in our in our world. We look at one
thing and we say, well, he must be mad
about it and it's like he said, man, I
just I was curious about how you're
going to use him. And then I showed him
how we're going to use him, you know,
and he's he's he's fired up about it,
but I I appreciated it, you know, I one
thing that you'll kind of probably see
as we go here,
you know, we don't get too worried about
stuff, you know, it's like as long as
long as a person's heart's in the right
place, as long as a person really cares,
a player, a coach, or anybody, and you
really you really want what's best for
everybody, you're coming from a good
he's got a good heart in a good place,
you know, say what you think, you know,
put it out there. We we talk all the
time about confronting everything that
has to do with our football.
And so,
Malik wants to know how we're going to
use our first round pick. I want to show
him. I want to explain it to him, you
know, and the fact he says it publicly,
who cares, you know, I know I know the
fans are probably thinking the same
thing. So, it was the same question that
that everybody's going to have and we
knew that, yeah, you know, cuz we we
knew that, you know, how kind of Arvell
was perceived. So, I think we I know
we've got a great vision for him and I
think we saw him I I it's just a it's
he's a player that fits our structure,
our defense very uniquely. And maybe
that's hard for people to see, but
you'll see it soon enough, you know, and
uh
and Malik was fired up about it and
happy. He was the first guy that met him
coming in the building when they when
they got in here. He couldn't wait to
get out there and just make sure they
knew, you know, that Arvell knew and his
family knew
uh where he was at with it. When you say
you showed him
that you really like that you like
put up tape and showed
>> No, no, I explained it to him, yeah. It
would have been a good idea to put up
some tape. That would have been fun. But
uh no, he could understand it, you know,
he knows ball.
Was it important
>> Left, left. You know, the guys came
through yesterday, the idea of, you
know, Cece said, you know, he met
Jackson. We saw the video he was with
Jackson. Abdul was here and so Reese.
How important was that? Was that organic
or did you guys kind of put it out there
and say, it'd be good for you guys to
come through when these guys are are
coming
>> Yeah, we have a great young nucleus of
guys that love ball and you know, they
they showed up on their own. A lot of
those guys showed up on their own and
we're excited to meet the new prospects
and welcome to the organization. So, it
was really cool to see those guys come
through and and and and meet their new
teammates and welcome with open arms.